Okay, so you now have some experience working
目前为止 你已经对处理缺失值积累了
with missing values and impeding based on some common methods.
一定的经验 使用过常用方法填充缺失值
And in this video we'll go through,
在这个视频当中
and see if we can use those imputation methods,
我们来看一下 填充缺失值
to do better than the dropping method that we used before.
会不会比直接删除缺失值的效果更好
And one big problem with dropping that we had before,
之前直接删除的一个很大的问题就是
was that we didn't actually predict on all of
我们实际上并没有针对所有的值进行预测
the values because if you didn't have a particular value in the X matrix,
因为只要缺少某个 X 矩阵中的值
then we basically just said we can't predict on you.
就没办法对其做出预测了
We're just going to drop you from the data set.
我们就直接将这些值从数据集中删除
Whereas with imputation we can put in something into those X values,
但如果对缺失值进行填充
and therefore predict a particular response.
就可以在完整的数据上做出预测
So, here's sort of the results that we had from before,
这里能够看到 之前使用删除缺失值方法得到的结果
and now let's see if we can't do better by following the directions here.
现在来看一下 如果我们遵循提示 能否获得更好的结果
So using the data frame from dropping the missing values according to the salary,
将 num_vars 中 Salary 缺失的数据删除
fill all the missing values with the mean,
用均值来填充其他列的缺失值
drop the rows with missing salaries.
删除缺失工资的行
So using the num_vars data frame,
使用 num_vars DataFrame
drop the missing values,
删除缺失值
drop the rows with missing values of the response.
删除目标变量缺失的数据行
So, when you use num_vars,
使用 num_vars
we want to drop NA on the subset equal to the salary,
调用 dropna 将 subset 设为 Salary
and we want to drop the rows associated with that.
我们想要删除相关的数据行
So X equals zero.
也就是 axis 要等于 0
So drop the rows with missing salaries,
将缺少工资的行删除
and then if we look at the results, okay that looks okay.
来看一下结果 看上去似乎不错
And then we can double check that that's right.
然后再用这个来检查一下
And here we want to fill in all of these NAs with the mean.
这里 我们要把所有缺失值的地方用均值来填充
So let's see if we can,
来看一下
so we can use what we did before.
我们可以复用之前的代码
So I'm just going to do fill_mean equals
也就是 fill_mean = lambda col: col.fillna(col.mean())
So if we take the mean of that column,
我们取某一列的均值
we fill it into that column, I think that should work.
然后将其填充到该列缺失值的位置
And so if we do this with drop_sal_df.apply(fill_mean, axis=1).
再用 drop_sal_df.apply(fill_mean, axis=1)
So it looks like that worked.
看看对不对
That wasn't what we expected,
结果与预期不相符
lets try axis equals zero.
再试下 axis = 0
There we go.
看看结果
Yeah, so axis equals zero.
是的 axis 的确要等于 0
We'll actually take the mean of the columns which is kind of strange,
我们实际计算的是每一列的均值 有点说不通
but I always get those confused.
不过我经常会弄混
So if we take axis equals zero.
所以把 axis 设为 0
We can see that we're filling in, let's see.
就可以看到缺失值被填充了
So these shouldn't have changed,
这些不应该改变
we're taking the average number of hours per week,
这里我用了周工作时长的均值
that people work which is apparently two point four four but
大家平均的周工作时长似乎是 2.44
if axis equals one, we should see.
但如果让 axis 等于 0 的话 我们会看到
Yeah, so this doesn't really make sense,
的确 这看上去就不合理了
28,000 hours per week.
28000 一周
That would be rough,
这也太多了
it doesn't make sense.
所以不合理
So when we did this,
如果我们这样做
we're getting the average by the columns.
就能得到每一列的均值
And now it says,
接下里的问题是
use fill_df to predict the salary for the quantitative variable.
用 fill_df 中的数值变量来预测工资
So the idea is now that we filled in all of these missing points,
这里的思路是 对缺失值进行填充
unlike what we had before where we had to drop all of these,
而不像之前做的那样 直接都删除掉
we should now be able to predict the salaries.
我们现在应该可以预测这些工资
Whereas before, our earlier model couldn't
之前的模型是不可以的
predict the salaries because we had missing values here and here.
因为这些数据中都存在缺失值
And so we'd actually end up dropping all of these as well.
之前我们实际上直接将这些数据删除了
But now we have values filled in for those,
但现在我们已经填充了这些值
even if they're just averages for those particular columns we should be able to predict.
尽管我们只是用均值做的填充 应该也是可以做预测的
So split into explanatory and response.
将数据划分为解释变量 X 和目标变量 y
So I'm just going to call X equal to fill_df and we want just the X variables.
仍然将其命名为 X 等于从 fillna 中筛选出所有数值变量
And then Y equal to fill_df_['salary'].
y = fill_df['Salary']
So here we're grabbing those X variables then we are pulling off the response,
这里只是把目标变量从数据集中拆分出来
and then we want to split this into training and test.
然后还要把它们分成训练集和测试集
So I always forget how this works and luckily there's an example up here.
我经常忘记这个要怎么写 还好上面有例子
And most of this should actually work the same.
这里的很多代码都可以复用
So once we call it X and Y,
创建 X 和 y 之后
then X and Y get past to this,
将 X 和 y 传入这个函数
this happens, this happens,
这个也需要 这个也需要
all of this stuff happens.
所有这些都可以复用
And if we label it all the same, yes,
给出的名称也是一样的
so they call it R-squared score.
R 平方值的变量名是 rsquared_score
So we can get this,
我们可以获取到
and then they want that length_Y_test,
然后还需要 length_y_test
so len(y_test_preds), and the R squared value should be this.
也就是 len(y_test_preds) 然后 R 平方应该是这里
So these are basically the two parts that are in this string they wanted.
这两个值应该就是题目要求的
And we still need to predict and score it.
我们还是需要做预测 给出评分
Okay, so predict and score, and then they also want the length stored in here.
预测并评分 然后还要求展示出样本的数量
I'm just going to put that all into this part.
把这些代码都放到一起
So it looks like we're predicting on 1,503 values which is more than the 645 from before.
这样看上去 我们对 1503 条数据进行了预测 比之前的 645 要多
And this only had
之前只有 2% 的差异性得到了解释 现在有 3.2% 了